( heavy metal doors clanging )
( girl breathing heavily ; running footsteps )
Aah !
Aaahhh !
( crying and screaming )
( analog soundtrack crackles )
MAN : Can we film ?
MAN # 2 : Whenever you 're ready , Doctor .
We 're in the chamfors industrial zone .
It was on this very spot that the child was found .
This is Building 1 .
We have prefectorial authorization to make this film
for the medical archives
of Assumption Hospital Pediatric Services .
Here we are .
This is where she lived .
She wasn ' t raped . That much is certain .
Otherwise it 's a classic case of child abuse .
Malnutrition , dehydration ,
mild hypothermia .
The hole allowed her to relieve herself .
The wrist infection indicates she was tied down .
MAN # 2 : But how did she get out ?
Lucie won ' t say what she endured .
( children talking and playing )
( crying softly )
MAN : Is that orange juice ?
Is it for her ?
Mais oui ,
You 're a regular little mommy .
She has no one now .
( projector whirring )
( projector motor stops )
Don 't worry , Anna , These gentlemen are very nice ,
Okay ,
MAN : You understand why we showed you this film ?
ANNA : Mm-hmm ,
MAN : Why do you think we need you ?
Because you want
to catch the people who hurt Lucie ?
That 's right , Anna ,
( whispering ) Lucie , too , She says you have to catch them ,
MAN : What else did she say ?
She 's scared ,
She tells you things ?
What does she remember ?
She doesn 't know who it was , Sometimes she thinks she remembers ,
sometimes she doesn 't ,
And what do you think ?
Can she remember ?
It was always dark , She couldn 't see much ,
She doesn 't remember ,
( man mutters affirmatively )
( knock on door )
Come in ,
Lucie Jurin didn 't come to lunch ,
Lucie ?
( soft whimpering )
( soft weeping )
Anna ,
Don 't tell anybody ,
Don 't do that ,
It wasn 't me ,
It wasn 't me , It wasn 't me ,
Calm down ,
( thunder rumbles )
Want to get in with me ?
( Lucie sighs )
( clock ticking )
( distant child crying out )
( child 's cries continue )
( sudden loud clatter )
( Lucie gasping )
Anna ?
( weeping softly )
( soft clatter )
( door hinges squeak softly )
( breathing nervously )
( Lucie gasps )
( whimpering )
( distant running footsteps )
( Lucie gasps )
( low , snarl-like breathing )
( shrieking )
1 5 YEARS LATER
( girl screaming )
( screaming )
( pursuer breathing heavily )
( girl screams )
( girl cries out )
Aah !
( laughing )
BOY : Give me that ! Give me that !
Ohh !
That 's enough , you two !
Pain in the ass !
His darling can 't write !
Stop it , I said ,
BOY : You rotten sister !
( boy speaking angrily )
( girl answers indistinctly )
You having breakfast or not ?
GlRL : We 're coming ,
( boy growling angrily )
" Marie Belfond regional 100-meter butterfly stroke champion "
( metal clanking on metal )
( groans with exertion )
MAN : That 's how you talk about it ?
How should I talk ?
Smartass ! And you wait until Sunday ,
Told your mother ?
Yeah ,
What does she say ?
That there 's a water pressure problem ,
When she goes all DlY , she 's not happy ,
- And you 're happy ? - Me ?
This is the high life ,
( boy mockingly repeats )
- WOMAN : Mission accomplished , - Great ,
Here ,
A gift from the chief ,
Oh , shit , Gabrielle !
It 's gross ,
In the main pipe ,
It explains the low shower pressure ,
Dump it , We 're eating ,
Mom !
It 's sickening , but we can put the garden back ,
Did Antoine mention his great plans ?
I was just asking what you thought ,
You were asking if she wasn 't mad ,
Keep out of this ,
But he 's my brother ,
Your darling brother 's a visionary ,
Right , Antoine ?
It 'll be an expensive school to leave after just three months ,
And with tuition paid in advance ,
Do you mind !
She made the headlines ,
- You gonna make this a habit ? - What ?
You needed prep school just to graduate ,
- You just scraped by , - But I graduated ,
A good thing , too , Remember what it cost ?
The checks each term ?
But did you give a damn ?
Aren 't you tired of being such a pain ?
But this school is different ,
I want to study something I like now ,
Nobody forced you ,
But law isn 't my thing ,
- Law opens every door , - That 's not the problem ,
He wants to live with his sweetheart ,
But law 's not my thing ,
If anything was your thing , we 'd know ,
You wanted to drop out to be a pastry cook , you dummy !
That 's below the belt !
( doorbell rings )
Who 's the pain in the ass ?
Language , Marie Belfond !
- It 's Sunday , after all , - So ?
What are you resting up from ?
A hard week at the factory ?
( Marie whimpering )
( Marie screams )
Don 't move !
Sit down ,
How old are you ?
18 ,
Know what your parents did ?
Huh ?
( Marie whimpering )
Aaahhh !
( crying )
( weeping softly )
How could you do that to me ?
How could you ?
( anguished shriek )
Why ?
( enraged scream )
( gunshot )
( pay telephone rings )
( ring )
- LUClE : It 's them . - Lucie ?
- It 's them , Anna . - You saw them ?
They 've changed , But it 's them ,
- You sure ? - I 'm telling you .
- It 's been 1 5 years , - It 's them .
- You can tell from a newspaper photo ? - Yes !
- Let 's call the cops , - No need .
- What ? - I did what I had to ,
- What ? - What I had to .
- You had to observe , You weren 't sure , - But I am sure .
I knew I should 've come along .
Why don 't you believe me ?
( weeping softly )
Where you calling from ?
- The house , - Their house ?
Yes ,
Give me the address ,
Give me the address !
( creaking sound )
( distant door clanks open )
( mysterious sound )
( hinges creaking )
( loud rasping sound )
( breathing heavily )
( short rasping sound )
( running footsteps )
I did it ,
( low , drawn-out rasping sound )
( low , congested breathing )
( loud shriek )
Aah !
( enraged shriek )
( fabric tears ; Lucie screams )
( raspy shriek )
( long raspy shriek )
( breathing heavily ; metallic thud )
( pounding on door ; Lucie screams )
( screams subside )
( pounding on door ; Lucie screams and weeps )
( distant banging sound )
( banging sound )
( breathing heavily )
( stifled scream )
( door opens )
Aaahhh !
It 's me , Lucie , Calm down , It 's me ,
She 's here ,
( Lucie crying )
- She 's in the house , - I know , I know ,
She hurt me even worse , Look !
Stay here ,
Where you going ?
- To take a look , - She 's in there ,
- I have to look , - She 's in there ,
Look at me , I have to look , Wait for me ,
( coughing and retching )
LUClE : Anna ?
LUClE : She hurt me worse than before ,
I 'm coming ,
LUClE : What will I do ?
( Anna weeping softly )
- LUClE : I 'm out of cartridges , - ANNA : Do without them ,
- Why don 't we leave ? - Come on ,
She 'll be back ,
Come on ,
You phoned me from the house , They 'll know it 's us ,
I don 't care ,
Right ,
If they lock you up , you 'll care ,
( Lucie hisses and groans )
- What will we do ? - Keep still ,
- It hurts , - Sorry ,
What will we do , Anna ?
Are you okay ?
Does it make you sick ?
Can you smell it ?
That awful smell ?
I 'd smell it when she bent over me ,
Every day , understand ?
When she 'd beat me , I 'd smell it ,
Look ,
It 's them ,
What are you doing ?
Will I ever be free of this ?
Yes , Yes ,
( groaning and struggling )
( crying out )
( distant thunder rumbles )
( steady rain falling )
( Anna grunts )
( grunting and straining )
( distant thunder rumbles )
( groans )
Aaahhh !
( crying out )
Anna ?
LUClE : Anna ?
Please , don 't make any noise ,
What are you up to ?
- You okay ? - Yeah ,
- I called you , - I was here ,
- I thought she 'd come back , - No ,
You finished ?
- Then we 'll go , - After we clean up ,
- Then we 'll go ? - Sure , Get dressed ,
( groaning )
( distant thunder rumbles )
( glass shatters )
LUClE : Aaahhh !
Aaahhh !
- Aaahhh ! - Lucie ?
Lucie ?
( glass shatters ; anguished scream )
( rasping shriek )
- Open up , Anna , - It 's locked ,
Open up ,
( Lucie screams ; rasping shriek )
Hurry !
No !
What do you want ?
Leave me alone !
I killed them ,
( misshapen thing shrieks )
Even their kids ,
I even killed their kids ,
Calm down , Calm down ,
( distant thunder rumbles )
( thunder crashes )
( loud metallic clank ; door hinges creaking )
( shrieking )
( Lucie screaming )
( woman screaming )
( long , despairing wail )
( continued wailing )
WOMAN : Don 't go in there , you little slut !
I 'll kill you !
( continued wailing )
( wailing )
Forgive me ,
It 's not my fault ,
( enraged wail )
( screaming )
( thunder crashes )
Anna ?
( pounding on door )
( anguished ) Anna !
Where are you ?
( enraged ) Anna !
I know you 're in there , Open up ,
ANNA : I 'm coming ,
( woman cries out )
( woman groaning and coughing )
What 's your name ?
Gabrielle ,
I 'm coming , Lucie ,
Help me , Gabrielle ,
Why did she do this ?
( glass shatters )
Aah !
ANNA : I think she heard us ,
Gabrielle !
We have to hurry ,
( creaking sound )
- An ambulance , - I can 't ,
For my children ,
I 'll take you as far as the woods , Then you 're on your own ,
ANNA : Don 't !
Don 't , Lucie !
( enraged screaming )
( weeping softly )
( steady rainfall outside )
Why did you help her ?
She didn 't do anything ,
She hurt me ,
Me !
( enraged scream )
And you want her to live ?
( weeping softly )
You never believed me ,
Stop it ,
You think I 'm crazy , just like the doctors ,
What did they ever do for me , apart from think me crazy ?
And you 're like them ,
It 's over , Anna ,
( misshapen thing groans )
( groans )
They 're dead ,
They won 't hurt you anymore ,
( long , rasping growl )
( drawer clatters ; box cutter clicks )
Aaahhh !
( Lucie cries out )
ANNA : Lucie !
Lucie !
( Lucie screaming )
( distant thunder rumbles )
ANNA : Lucie !
Stop !
No !
No ! No !
( sniffling )
( dipping sponge in water )
( birds chirping )
WOMAN : Why are you calling ?
Not a word from you in two years ...
- ... and now you call ? - Yes ,
I 'm furious with you . I won 't hide it .
Mom ,
Trying to make me feel guilty ?
No ,
Think I don 't blame myself ?
Think my head 's not filled with all the crap I did ?
That 's not it , Mom ,
Then what ?
I wanted to talk to you , I just felt like it ,
So one morning you decide you miss your mother ?
So you 're okay ? Not in trouble ?
No ,
You sure ? Where are you ?
Pretty far away ,
Where do you sleep ? How do you live ?
- I 'm okay , - You still with her ?
- You 're under her influence . - No ,
christ ! You 're still with her . It 's the same thing .
Mom !
( loud clanking sound )
That girl 's a good-for-nothing .
She 's a bitch , a pervert , a loser ...
Get away from her .
Anna ?
WOMAN : Allo ?
Allo ?
( distant , faint clanking sound )
( chain rattles )
( stifled cry )
( whimpering )
( chain falls to floor )
( pitiful weeping )
ANNA : Don 't move ,
ANNA : I can 't help you ,
( panicked cries )
Don 't be afraid , Shh ,
( pained groans )
Aaahhh !
( metal clatters to floor )
Aah !
ANNA : Shh , Calm down ,
Shh ,
Rest ,
Forgive me ,
( birds chirping )
( distant pained moan )
( moaning continues )
( pained moan )
Stop it !
( muffled shrieks )
( gunshot )
Who 's the girl on the couch ?
Who ?
Lucie ,
Lucie who ?
Lucie Jurin ,
And you ?
Anna Assaoui ,
We 've been calling for hours ,
The phone was off the hook ,
This shouldn 't have happened ,
Can you tell me what went on here ?
What are you doing here ?
( distant bird caws )
( metal creaking and clanking )
( footsteps approaching )
Lucie Jurin escaped us 1 5 years ago ,
didn 't she ?
Didn 't she ?
Ouais .
A time when we were , shall we say , less organized ,
Gabrielle shouldn 't have let her get away , The child found her ,
After 1 5 years , that takes some doing ,
As for the rest ,
Lucie is only a victim ,
Like all the others ,
It 's so easy to create a victim , young lady , so easy ,
You lock someone in a dark room ,
They begin to suffer ,
You feed that suffering ,
methodically ,
systematically , and coldly ,
And make it last ,
Your subject goes through a number of states ,
After a while , their trauma ,
that small , easily opened crack
makes them see things that don 't exist ,
What did your poor Lucie see ?
Nothing ?
Not even a monster or two ?
Things that wanted to hurt her ?
Hmm ?
A dead girl ,
There you are ,
The girl you found , Sarah Dutreuil , kept seeing cockroaches
running all over her ,
She 'd have cut her arm off rather than bear that ,
People no longer envisage suffering , young lady ,
That 's how the world is ,
There are nothing but victims left ,
Martyrs are very rare ,
A martyr is something else ,
Martyrs are extraordinary beings ,
They survive pain , they survive total deprivation ,
They bear all the sins of the earth ,
they give themselves up ,
they transcend themselves ,
Do you understand that word ?
They are transfigured ,
Long Sheng Province , 1912 ,
This woman didn 't believe in God ,
She tried to steal a hen , It cost her dearly ,
When this photo was taken , she was still alive ,
Look at her eyes ,
Jouans-Lussac , 1945 , This woman was a grocer ,
She slept with a Kraut , At that time , the French
were touchy , She had to pay ,
She was alive ,
Look at her eyes ,
Birmingham Hospital , 1960 ,
An ordinary housewife , an atheist , in the terminal stages
of cancer , Morphine has no effect now ,
Look at her eyes ,
Beaten by her husband in a state of jealous rage ,
Nine hours in a car wreck ,
A young leukemia victim in her final moments ,
Stricken with a rare disease ,
Nine hours of agony ,
Look at her eyes ,
All of them , young lady , You hear me ?
They were all alive when photographed ,
Don 't try to tell me that the notion of martyrdom
is an invention of the religious ,
We tried everything , even children ,
It turns out that women ,
, are more responsive to transfiguration ,
Young women ,
That 's how it is , young lady ,
( muffled cries )
( coughing softly )
( soft cry of despair )
Aah !
Aaahhh !
Aaaaahhhhh !
( screaming continues )
Aaahhh !
Aaaaahhhhh !
( crying softly )
( distant metal creaking and clanking )
( ongoing metallic ringing )
( ringing subsides )
( ladder clattering )
( Anna groans )
Aah !
( metal ladder clanking )
( urine flows )
( metal ladder slides )
( Anna weeping softly )
( heavy blow lands ; Anna coughing )
( gasps )
( metal clanking )
( weeping softly )
( soft weeping continues )
( metal ladder slides )
( Anna spits out food )
( soft , frustrated cries )
( metal ladder sliding )
( gasps )
( Anna weeping softly )
( muttering softly )
LUClE : Anna ?
Are you there ?
ANNA : I 'm here .
LUClE : Anna ?
ANNA : Yes , Lucie ?
LUClE : Why are you never scared ?
ANNA : I am scared sometimes .
LUClE : Not like me .
ANNA : I didn 't go through what you did .
How do you stop being scared ?
LUClE : Let yourself go , I think .
ANNA : You think so ?
LUClE : Let yourself go .
ANNA : And if I can 't , will you be there ?
LUClE : Yes .
I miss you ,
( metal ladder slides )
LUClE : You 're not scared anymore .
You 're not scared anymore .
Not scared anymore .
You 'll be all right , Anna ,
You 'll be all right ,
Your suffering is almost over ,
There 's one more stage ,
The last one ,
You 'll be all right , You won 't have to protect yourself ever again ,
It 's okay , Anna ,
( no audible groan or scream )
( soft gasping , amplified )
- WOMAN : She still bearing up ? - MAN : Amazing ,
( distant , faint metallic clanging )
( woman screaming )
WOMAN : Michel !
MlCHEL : What is it ?
Just now , I went down to feed her ,
- MADEMOlSELLE : Are you sure ? - It 's like I said ,
I 've never seen an expression like it ,
She 's let go , completely let go , Her face is like ,
Mademoiselle ,
her eyes , I swear , she no longer sees anything around her ,
But is she still ...
She 's alive , Mademoiselle ,
( preternatural rumbling sound )
( gasping softly )
( distant rumbling sound )
( child cries out )
( brakes screech )
( distant thunder rumbles )
( fluid trickling softly )
Did you see ?
The other world ?
( inaudible whisper )
( distant bird caws )
( caw )
Yesterday afternoon ,
in this very house ,
at around 12 : 1 5 p , m ,
Anna Assaoui was martyred ,
Let us pay our respects ,
Anna Assaoui is an exceptional being ,
In 1 7 years of endeavors ,
she is only the fourth to have attained that stage ,
And the first - - yes , my friends - -
the first to relate what she has seen ,
Between 12 : 15 and 2 : 30 p , m ,
Miss Assaoui clearly saw what lay beyond death ,
You heard me , Her state of ecstasy
Iasted two hours and 15 minutes , This was not
a near-death experience ,
She experienced authentic martyrdom ,
At 2 : 30 p , m , she came out of this state ,
At 3 : 05 p , m ,
she spoke ,
At this very moment ,
she is still alive ,
But she has stopped communicating ,
Mademoiselle heard her testimony ,
That testimony , dear friends ,
will be shared with you in a moment ,
Mademoiselle ,
they 're all waiting ,
I 'm coming , Etienne ,
So there is something ,
Of course ,
Was it clear ?
Crystal clear ,
And precise ?
It admitted of no interpretations , Etienne ,
Thank you , Mademoiselle ,
Etienne ?
Mademoiselle ?
Could you imagine what there is after death ?
Are you all right ?
- Could you ? - No , Mademoiselle ,
Keep doubting ,
( gunshot )
Martyr : noun , from the Greek " marturos " :
Witness
( movie projector whirring )
SEPPUKU PARADlGM : There was no tender age
It was tough from the start
But you 're holding my hand
We 're all that we have
I cry when you bleed
And I bleed when you cry
I don 't want to lie
I love what you are
I would do anything
Give you everything
I 've seen where you 've been in your eyes
Your bruises and cuts
They 're ghosts from the past
There 's nowhere to run
Nowhere to hide
The pain will go ' way
Yet I slowly realize
I miss you so deeply
I want to be where you are
I will do anything
Give up everything
I 've seen through this hell of your eyes
Of your eyes
Your eyes
Live till the day that you die
( movie projector shuts off )